Kathryn Costantin

Charleston, SC

1 (202) 420-1727 | ☐ costantinkp@gmail.com | in linkedin.com/in/costantinkp | github.com/ktllama

Career Profile

Creative and outgoing Web Developer ensuring 100% customer satisfaction and high-quality user experience. Highly effective communicator focused on tackling humanitarian issues through technological means. Translating idealism into pragmatic applications for business and marketing outcomes through full-stack development. Cross-cultural and highly adaptive problem solver working with diverse cultures, backgrounds, and age groups to help increase accessibility and navigation of the ever-growing world wide web and mobile applications.

Experience

Habitat for Humanity

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/ UX UI DESIGN

Charleston, South Carolina June 2021 - October 2021

- Designed, developed and maintained company website with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Square Space.
- Using SEO and google analytics, structured website to increased donations and volunteer applications by 30%
- Enhanced user experience through UX and UI optimization of navigation, searchability, functionality, and responsiveness.

Los Volcanes Coffee, Inc.

INTERNAL JOURNALIST, MEDIA MANAGER, DIRECTOR OF EDUCATION

Antiqua, Guatemala June 2018 - Feb. 2020

- Photographer and manager of social media accounts. Created and designed website.
- Through interviews, photography and intensive documentation- created traceable marketing material for clients.
- Hosted educational events for farmers and clients- acted as point of contact for US and Guatemalan clients.
- Managed the G suites, Google Drive, calendar, photos and documents for the 146 farms and communities we work with.

Breakthrough Public Charter School

LEAD PRIMARY GUIDE

Washington, D.C. Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2017

- Founding member of a Breakthrough Charter School and classroom of 25 primary age children.
- Managed online portal for communication with parents and educational development.

Education

Full-stack Mobile and Web Developer Bootcamp

BOOTSTAP, REACT, REACT NATIVE, NODE.JS, MONGO DB

NuCamp Present

Master of Education, Loyola University

Baltimore, MD 2016

AMI MONTESSORI CERTIFICATION, PRIMARY

Boone, NC 2014

B.A. International Studies, Appalachian State University MINOR:: SPANISH

Boone, NC 2014

B.A. Sustainable Development, Appalachian State University

MINOR: APPROPRIATE TECHNOLOGY

Certifications

HTML5 and CSS3, Responsive Design2021 Interactivity with JavaScript, 2021 Python Data Structures, 2021 **Technical Support Fundamentals**, 2021 TESOL/TEFL, 2015

University of Michigan University of Michigan University of Michigan Google Certification University of Maryland

Skills

Front-End: Bootstrap React CSS3 HTML5 JavaScript GIT/Github WordPress Design: **GIMP** Figma Photography Canva Other: VS Code Slack Microsoft Office Blogging Google Workspace